Today we're asking the question at the very center of the Christian faith, who is Jesus,
according to His own words in the Bible.
This is not just a matter of opinion, it is a matter of eternal life or death.
It's the line between the Creator and the creature, between the Kingdom of God and the
kingdoms of this world.
The Bible says that, in the fullness of time, the eternal Son of God took on human flesh.
Before He was born in Bethlehem, He existed forever, sharing the same divine nature as
God the Father and the Holy Spirit.
He is the Maker of heaven and earth.
Everything was created through Him, and everything holds together because of Him.
And yet He stepped into His own creation, not as a distant ruler, but as a real man,
born into a humble Jewish family in Bethlehem, in Israel, under Roman occupation.
People could count His years on earth, but His divine life had no beginning and will
have no end.
Jesus was not just a wise teacher or a prophet.
The Bible also calls Him the Christ, the Greek word for Messiah, which means God's
promised and chosen Savior, the one promised to deliver His people from their sins.
When He said, Before Abraham was, I am, He was claiming the very name of God revealed
to Moses.
The prophets had promised a king who would reign forever, called Mighty God and Prince
of Peace.
In Jesus those promises came true, not partially, but completely.
When Jesus called God His Father in a unique way, He was declaring that He is equal with
God.
That was not arrogance, it was truth.
The Creator had taken on the nature of His creation without ever ceasing to be God.
The Bible calls this the Incarnation, not man ascending to God, but God descending to
man.
The Eternal Word became flesh.
He knew what it was to be hungry, thirsty, tired, and deeply moved with compassion.
And yet He never sinned.
Sin is breaking God's perfect standard for how we are to live.
As Jesus explained in His own words, to love God with all our heart, soul, mind, and strength,
and to love others as ourselves.
We have all failed to do this, and because of that we stand guilty before Him, deserving
not only physical death, but spiritual and eternal separation from God.
This is why Jesus came to save us from sin and reconcile us to God.
Every one of us, represented by the first man Adam, has sinned in this way.
Our sin has separated us from our Creator, and no one but the God-man could bridge that
infinite gap.
Why only Jesus?
Because the gap between a holy God and sinful humanity is not just moral, it is infinite.
No mere human could perfectly live according to God's standard, and no one but Jesus has
done this without failure.
And no one but Jesus could bear the full weight of God's righteous judgment and then rise
victorious over death.
The Bible makes it clear that only one who is truly righteous can stand in the place
of the guilty.
Jesus confirmed this when He said,
I am the way, and the truth, and the life.
No one comes to the Father except through me.
In all of history, only Jesus is both fully God, able to bear the infinite cost, and fully
man, able to represent us.
No one is saved by their own works, good intentions, or religious efforts.
The Bible says,
By grace you have been saved through faith.
And this is not your own doing, it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that
no one may boast.
Our hope rests entirely on what Jesus has done, not on what we have done.
On the cross, under the authority of the Roman governor Pontius Pilate, Jesus was sentenced
to death and crucified, a brutal form of execution reserved for the worst criminals in the Roman
Empire.
Yet this was no accident of history.
The Romans carried it out, but it was according to the definite plan and foreknowledge of
God.
In that moment, Jesus bore the full weight of God's wrath against sin.
He was not forced there by chance or injustice.
He gave his life willingly.
He was carrying out the plan the Father had made before the foundation of the world, to
save us from sin and reconcile us to God.
As the Bible says,
For God so loved the world that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should
not perish but have eternal life.
And then, on the third day, he rose from the grave.
The resurrection was not just a symbol of hope, it was the final victory over death,
the proof that every claim he made was true, and the declaration that his sacrifice for
us was accepted by God.
It showed that the penalty for sin, which God's word declares is death, had been paid
in full for all who trust in him.
Today Jesus reigns at the right hand of the Father.
He is not waiting to be king, he is king now.
From his throne he rules over all creation and continues his work in the lives of his
people through the Holy Spirit.
As he promised his disciples, I will not leave you as orphans, I will come to you.
He has kept that promise by sending the Holy Spirit to dwell within all who belong to him.
He gives us new desires that align with God's will, transforms our patterns of thinking,
and renews our minds so that we may have the mind of Christ.
He leads us to walk in obedience, strengthens us in trials, and conforms us to his image
day by day.
And one day every knee will bow before him, either in joy and faith or in fear and judgment.
But his reign now is only the beginning of what he will accomplish.
The Bible promises that one day Jesus will return in glory, not in humility, to judge
the living and the dead.
He will raise his people to eternal life, wipe away every tear, and bring in the new
heavens and the new earth where God's righteousness dwells.
For those who belong to him, the future is filled with unshakable hope.
We will see him face to face, be fully freed from sin, and dwell with him forever.
So the question is not just, who is Jesus?
It is, who do you say that he is?
The Bible says,
Salvation is not about what you can do for God, but about what God has already done for
you in Christ.
To turn away from him is to remain under God's righteous judgment.
To trust him is to be reconciled to your Creator, saved from your sin, and welcomed into his
eternal kingdom.
If you have never trusted in Jesus, I desire with all my heart that you would turn to him
today.
Believe in him, follow him, and discover the joy of knowing him.
He calls you not only to be forgiven but to walk with him, to enjoy his presence, and
to share the good news of his salvation with others.
This is the life you were created for, to glorify God and to delight in him forever.
This is who Jesus is, the eternal Son of God, the image of the invisible God, the Lord over
all things, the only Savior for sinners, the one before whom heaven and earth will one
day stand in judgment.
If the Spirit of God has touched your heart today, do not ignore his voice.
Help a sincere and intimate relationship with him and enjoy his perfect and unfailing love.
Start by getting to know him, open the Bible, and read the passages we have mentioned in
the Gospel of John chapter 8 verse 58, in the Book of Isaiah the prophet chapter 9 verses
6 and 7, in the Letter to the Romans chapter 3 verses 23 and 24, in the Gospel of John
chapter 14 verses 6 and 18, in the Letter to the Ephesians chapter 2 verses 8 and 9,
in the Gospel of John chapter 3 verse 16, in the Letter to the Romans chapter 10 verse
9.
Read them prayerfully, asking God to open your eyes to the truth of his Word.
The Bible declares that the penalty for sin is death, not just physical death but spiritual
and eternal separation from God.
Yet in his love, God has provided the only way to be forgiven and reconciled to him through
his Son, Jesus Christ.
Cry out to him in prayer.
Ask him to forgive you for your sin, to give you the grace to repent, to turn away from
sin and turn toward him, and to come into your life as your Lord and Savior.
Trust fully in what Jesus has done for you, his perfect life, his death in your place,
and his resurrection from the dead, and follow him from this day forward.